Adam Blalock

Web Designer

Address: 911 San Pablo Way

Novato, CA 94949

Email: adamrblalock@gmail.com

Phone: (415) 250-0896

Date of Birth: 07-04-1986

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/adam-blalock-

abb757146/

Self-starter who loves a challenge, such as developing a website used by hundreds of students while also completing a PhD! I love to combine my passion for programming with my background in psychology/neuroscience to design elegant web applications that are centered on user experience.

Software Development Experience

2014 – present Web Application Developer

ClassQuestion.com (self-employed)

Founder and lead developer of <u>ClassQuestion.com</u>, a website for conducing polls and gathering real-time student feedback during college lectures. I performed all of the frontend and back-end programming myself using:

- Front-end: HTML, CSS, Javascript/jQuery
- Backend: Flask/Python, SQLAlchemy, MySQL, and Redis
- A unique combination of AJAX, Server-Sent Events, and Redis, is used to allow questions to be sent to student devices, as well as collect and display their answers in real-time

2015 – present Independent Game Developer

Self-Employed

Developer of a first-person action game using the Unity3D game engine. Game-play involves first-person shooting combined with tower-defense and physics-based building construction.

I've developed the game using

- Unity 3D
- Game-play programming using C#
- 3D modeling and animation using Blender
- UI and textures creation using GIMP, Photoshop, and Illustrator
- Alpha demo available at https://bit.ly/2GS7gfC

Education

2014 – 2017	Ph.D. in Cognitive Neuroscience, University of California, Davis
2011 – 2013	M.A. in Cognitive Neuroscience, University of California, Davis
2005 – 2010	B.S. in Psychology - Biological Emphasis, University of California, Davis

Skills

- HTML (4 years)
- CSS (4 years)
- Javascript & jQuery (4 years)
- Python & Flask (4 years)
- C# (4 years)

- MySQL (3 years)
- Redis (1 year)
- Adobe Illustrator (3 years)
- Adobe Photoshop (2 years)

Other Work Experience

2016 – 2018 College Lecturer

University of California, Davis

Developed and taught undergraduate courses in psychology and cognitive science at U.C. Davis.

Lead instructor for:

- Introduction to Psychology (Spring 2016, Winter 2017)
- Cognitive Psychology (Summer 2017)
- Language and Cognition (Fall 2017, Winter 2018)

2011 - 2017 Graduate Student Researcher

University of California Davis

- Conducted experiments in the fields of Cognitive Neuroscience, Neurolinguistics, and Psychology of Language.
- Completed a PhD dissertation using EEG (Electroencephalography) combined with ANOVA and regression analysis to examine the role that individual variation in working memory capacity and cognitive control contributes to how individuals process the context of a story.